ABOUT ME

I'm a passionate and enthusiastic developer with experience in full-stack development. I have a wide range of experience starting from designing and building small web sites to architect scale real-time web and mobile apps. I continue improving my Javascript stack, with Reactjs, React Native, and Node.js. I try to expand in my area of expertise every day and I'm not afraid to learn new things.

CONTACT



+55 92 98418-2160



jilvan.silva@gmail.com



@jilvanx github.com/jilvanx



https://jilvanx.github.io

SKILLS

React

•

React Native

Node.js

PHP

Java

Angular 2+

Jest

Cypress

Docker

RabbitMO

Apache Kafka

Git

JILVAN CÂNDIDO DA SILVA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer - Invillia

since May 2020

I was in charge of developing and maintaining client applications using Next.js (React) with Styled Components and Jest for unit test on the frontend. Scrum for agile project management methodology and Github for version control.

Tech Leader - ICTS - Institute of Technology

since December 2019 - April 2020

Responsible for monitoring activities and delivering the energy efficiency project that makes up a real-time monitoring solution using IoT. Participation in the architecture and definition of technologies used in the project such as Node.js, React.js, React Native, Kafka, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Redis, Docker and Jest for tests. For DevOps activities I used Google Cloud Platform to host containers. Scrum for agile project management methodology and Gilab for version control.

Full Stack Developer - FIT - Institute of Technology

since March 2018 - November 2019

I was responsible for developing and maintaining an industrial application that collected production, inventory, and financial data, processed the information, and displayed it on a dashboard for management decision making. I used docker to build the microservices and host on the Google Cloud platform. I used Node.js and Spring Boot (JAVA) in the backend and React.js and React Native in the frontend. For unit testing I used Jest. I used scrum for agile project management methodology, JIRA for error management and BitBucket for version control.

Full Stack Developer - SENAI - AM

since December 2014 - February 2018

I worked as a front-end developer to maintain the companies home page. I made some custom queries and optimization of procedures on the SQL server to extract data to use on reports. I used Scrum for agile framework management and Github for version control.

EDUCATION

Learn how to test javascript applications - Jest and Cypress

September 2020

https://javascript.tv.br

Node.js, Express, React, React Native, MongoDB and Docker.

Abril 2019 Rocketseat

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

March 2000 - December 2004

UNIP - Brazil